[Music]
all right we should be going
you know streaming it's um
still new to me it's still still very
new to me hopefully hopefully we're all
good it is eight o'clock that means it
is the Hermit Craft stream day those of
you coming over from Concord welcome
welcome welcome welcome welcome welcome
welcome and you've got me for about two
hours before we then pass you on to Red
Dog and welcome so I'm I'm down here in
my this is like my miniature green style
training hall except it's not really
trading hall this is just my emerald
farm I guess it gives me potatoes it
gives me carrots and I've actually
upgraded it and unfortunately this dream
comes at a pretty inconvenient time
because tomorrow I have a pretty big
episode coming out with blimey a lot of
things a lot of things coming out
there's a there's a big time-lapse which
we'll talk about a bit later there's a
lot of Sherlock green going on so uh
neva tably this livestream will contain
spoilers for those of you that don't
know but most of you will know it takes
me a really really really long time to
make one episode of hermitcraft I'm just
a slow worker
basically and yeah it means that there's
ultimately spoilers just because the
episode comes out tomorrow instead of
today anyway this is basically what I do
here I just trade all my potatoes and
carrots and stuff and I get myself
pumpkins from up above so that's a bit
of a spoiler cuz I worked on that just
casually I guess up here I made another
tube the pump pump to pump good the
pumpkin tube it's not very efficient I
didn't actually do a very good job I
should have made this wider should have
made that one over but I thought I was
doing a good job but basically pumpkins
get stuck on it I can't she see any
yeah they get they get stuck which is
really rather quite annoying
however there so that's already one
spoiler taken care of but I mean it
wasn't exactly the highlight of my
episode tomorrow don't you worry all
right so let's get started let's get you
let's get rid of all these carrots and
potatoes etc we've got lots of things
and there's already donations coming
through massively oh geez I forgot about
those why do I private my old streams no
I don't like the old one is still up
there but here's the thing
it took YouTube over a week like eight
days to put it on my channel utterly
ridiculous it took such a long time
anyway there's no what we're gonna be
working on is the Sahara project if
you've been watching the stream day
you've already seen the progress so big
spoilers we've done a lot of work to it
and there's actually a big gap here that
still needs doing so that's basically
what we're going to be doing today in
today's stream at least that oh yeah so
earlier in the stream mumbo like arrived
in style on one of these and I left it
here because I wanted to I wanted to
learn learn this way there's nothing
more dangerous than me learning how to
do a flying machine so I was gonna I was
gonna reverse engineer this and see what
I could do anyway so yeah let's just get
the spoilers over and done with because
I mean ultimately it's just it's already
happened people have already shown it on
their stream especially ask our mumbo so
look here it is this is Sahara HQ it's
got the architect logo in the middle it
took a long time for us to actually
figure out what this would end up
looking like and I'm pretty pleased with
how it looks it all it all and it's
obviously taking a lot of concrete but
I'm hoping that we can get this a bit
more finished by the time by the time we
end and pass over to Rennes so yeah this
is what it's gonna look this is what
like building in the background looks
like I'd normally obviously time-lapse
this sort of stuff but me
you'd know we're gonna get a first hand
so I spent a bit of time gathering some
materials that I think we might need in
these schalke boxes I think we should
start round the back here so the
thinking the problem is with this is we
don't exactly know apart from the
redstone so the redstone is going in
this big bit here that's wise
there's absolutely massive space I don't
have to worry about this thankfully I
don't have to worry about this one
little bit however I do have to worry
about this bit over here that's a total
mess at the moment so hopefully we can
come up with a few ideas for rooms and
I'm thinking this out here needs to be
completely terraformed and a lot of
people are saying Sahara looks great
thank you so much me mumbo myself mumbo
and it's cow all helped build it at the
same time cannot claim all the credit
okay so I guess we could get started I
mean one of the things that I definitely
wanted to do was get rid of all this
snow up here put it as wool I don't
really like either discuss that we could
do snow on the top instead of this but I
was liking too late already done carpet
so I don't know we did carpet over there
maybe it just seems right it's not
really the big deal at the end of the
day so that's let's crack on with some
more boring bits we'll do a little bit
first as we've just started and then
we'll we'll move on to the building's
layer mainly because I'm not entirely
sure what I want to make out the back
there it's it might be a little bit
trial and error normally these things
have to be planned out somewhat lots of
donations coming through I want to thank
everybody that is donating that's
amazing oh man that's that didn't get
get us very far did it let's keep going
so how is everyone how is everyone doing
this is my second ever hermit craft
stream which is terrifying
not experienced streamer so if you do
donate and I do miss it I do profusely
apologize but yeah Sahara is definitely
underway in a big way
we are we are on we are definitely we
are definitely doing quite well here
Oh rent says my game sounds a bit oh it
is down because it's often too loud in
my ear should we put some minecraft
music on you know I normally turn this
off because I cut so frequently maybe
that that's probably due loud but if the
minecraft music comes on so be it if it
annoys anyone we'll turn it off again
but I normally keep it off because I cut
so much so like when I'm recording
obviously if it just starts with the
nostalgia kicks in you know then it cuts
and it's gone it can be really like
disruptive so I don't normally well no I
never play with the minecraft music on
let me know if there's any problems with
the sound at all I'm just gonna 31 is
where I normally where I normally have
it anyway right let's continue that
didn't do very like this is not gonna be
enough wool at all I mean I maybe I
should have gone snow I don't know I'm a
fool sometimes the game sounds are a bit
too loud now Wren next time just did
leave it where it is leave me leave me
to Rena I'd rather have it to quiet than
to loud
my my my commentary is that is the main
main thing anyway let's have a look so
someone said put string on the ceiling
that would look really odd and I I think
that would look really strange I don't
like the the carpet really doesn't
matter too much I don't think I really
don't think it's that bad it's obviously
not ideal but overall when it's
completely finished not a big deal not a
big deal all right let's oh man I've
only done like a few stacks and I'm
already
I'm already burnt out on this
for some reason okay so when I normally
am when I normally time-lapse the
building of these kinds of things I
usually listen to an audio book or I
listen to some music but now I have to
talk unprecedented unprecedented oh my
goodness I need to read some of these
donations so so it's a great great work
cool mumbo yeah obviously the the
coolbrian cool mumbo thing this is never
gonna end is it although I do love I do
love winding up mumbos chat I really do
you're all you got to do is write cool
green in the chat and it sets everybody
off it sets everyone off man right we're
gonna do a little bit of this and then
we're gonna go back to go back over
there and work on the courtyard area see
we've got a lot of just space to fill
you see TF sees bass is right here and
his little wooden shack there and what
we didn't realize when we set up here is
that his bass not only just goes
straight down but it also spreads
underground to about here maybe it is
really really actually quite large under
there so that's why sahara has ended up
being the shape that it is so that we
don't bump into him and ruin any of his
work so we've kind of got to come up
with a big project i suppose or
courtyard space here so that we don't
bump into him and that's why this is at
the back and then we're gonna have the
shop front here so this space has got to
be filled up which is gonna be a bit of
a challenge right so over here I'm gonna
have to sleep on this this area we've
learned is really really dangerous so
when we were recording the time-lapse I
guess spoilers again what happened was
we had this one tiny dark patch
the the the roof there and all sixty
mobs of the the mob cap limit spawned in
this tiny tiny space and it was chaos it
was absolutely chaos we couldn't cope
and a scale like did a one-man battle
while I watched it was pretty it was
cool anyway I was thinking of doing a
few trees like really tall trees cuz
this is one big gray wall I mean if I
press yeah there you go look that is one
big grey wall so I'm thinking what we
could do and I just have to remember
where I put the leaves right here I'm
thinking what we do is we do some custom
trees to decorate this a bit so I'm
thinking they need to be quite tall they
do need to be quite tall these trees in
order for it to in order for it to
actually make a dent in this which is
why I've planned out this giant patch of
grass here this is obviously like fake
in quotations fake grass I mean this
isn't real grass but this is like the
like if you've mowed the lawn kind of
thing this is like the back and forth
pattern I don't know the right words for
these things now I think this might be a
two-block Center it is it is alright
we'll put the we'll put the trees
forward one so one two three four let's
just test the spacing first I think
maybe five actually just looking at that
alright now this is something
embarrassing that I do on minecraft I
don't know if anyone else does this but
I have to like hit the block and count
one two three four five so five block
gap that's not gonna be big enough I can
already tell that's not gonna be big
enough at all so has to get one two
three four five six seven maybe seven
let's take a step back because what
you've got to imagine is that these
trees are gonna go up and they're gonna
kind of circle around so I think maybe
so that's that's eight nine ten so let's
have a gap of ten that should be ten
three four five six seven eight nine
yep so let's try and have a little
visualize of that and oh my goodness
someone donated 9999
is through super chat that was alpha
Alex you're amazing green and truly a
quality youtuber was that hope you are
do I like big Chung's I don't I don't
know what that is
hopefully you're having a great day and
tell mumbo to get a new outfit
he doesn't need a new outfit yeah I
don't think Mambo needs a new outfit his
suit is slick he I mean that's the great
thing like me and me and Isco ah that's
yeah see here's the thing when you're
holding an axe you're you're when you're
holding wood or logs you want to hold an
axe at the same time it's just like
association hey um I always just I
always just right-click although it
might look decent I don't know whether
to go stripped oak or normal oak hmm I
think that looks more natural but this
might fit in more hmm maybe we could try
both because I mean the the thing is I'm
placing leaves so they're not gonna
decay they're not gonna decay at all so
the oplog I mean I can always just take
it down and put put it back there really
easily so let's just yeah let's go for
the stripped oak shall we so like that
oh that's rather satisfying you could
make a remix out of that for sure right
how tall do we want to go because
remember we don't want to go all the way
we don't wanna go all the way up here if
for the the log we also have like quite
a long way to go up with the leaves now
this is gonna look really bad this is
just gonna look like a pillar whoo whoo
whoo whoo whoo that's a terrible looking
thing if I've ever seen one yeah but
that's the basis of our tree anyway that
actually might be the right size all it
might actually be a little bit too tall
I reckon we probably want to go about as
tall as that so we'll get rid of that
and sort of shift all those leaves down
there
and that's that's where we're gonna
start hmm all right this is a this is
where the skill comes in on flying and
it's probably not gonna happen but can
we landing on one blocks one block is
not easy to do come on come on server
give me my wings all right round two
ladies and gentlemen of the trying to
land on one block if we don't do this
yes oh we did it okay right then we go
again we're gonna make this a little bit
shorter this time we're gonna make this
a little bit shorter about at all maybe
and then three four five six I mean it's
easy to shave the bit off the top there
probably a bit lower probably too low
this is like this is where like just it
comes in just eyes you gotta just I I oh
yeah this is the stream day torch that
they passed on to me cub and scar I had
to rename it because I was like what
happens if I put it down on the floor
and take it back again and it obviously
reset the name so I've um I've had to
rename it but I'm sure I'm sure it's
fine it's exactly the same torch though
is this no beep all right so the shape
that we want to try and get is it kind
of goes up and you know the kind of tree
I'm talking about it's it kind of goes
like a little bit of roundness to it but
then it's mostly really pointy I've
actually got a reference picture I need
to just hold on a sec I need to just
I've got a screenshot of one that I made
and I just need to check it because you
know reference pictures help quite a lot
hold on
there we go I've got a bright got that
up there we go sorry Chris Chris Stewart
donated ten pounds and said it's Marge
Simpson as a tree yo you are right you
are absolutely correct
it is Marge Simpson as a tree it's her
it's her hair just not blue it's green
thank you very much for the the donation
there that's very kind of you very kind
indeed
okay so right we're gonna put Marge
Simpson's hair on a tree that's exactly
what we're gonna do
so yeah I've got I've got my my
reference picture but the problem is my
reference picture has some like well
then at trickery going on as well so
like there's like leaves on it as sorry
not leaves
mate leaves it's got grass on it which
helps like make it look a bit more
texture them hairy I guess you know the
branches coming out this is gonna be a a
bit difficult but like it when you make
trees there's no fine art one of the
biggest like bits of advice I can give
for anyone making trees is when you when
you go ahead and make tree the reason
minecraft trees don't look amazing is
because they're very uniform so if you
go ahead and do a tree and it's like
it's perfect all the way around and it
looks like that
then it's that's that's where the trees
start to look a little bit on the
unnatural side but as soon as you like
add some variation in and like just a
few blocks missing one that sticks out
it starts to look a lot more natural of
course I don't have any shears to take
this back but hopefully that explains it
a bit better
all right let's crack on with this then
so I kind of like the bottom here I'm
gonna remove that one I mean it's just
gonna be a bit of it's kind of like an
abstract painting in some respects you
just you just whack the leaves on there
and see what you get although I haven't
got an unlimited amount so I'm not gonna
tell her off with this I was gonna mix
in some leaves but I might do that very
occasionally just for a bit of texture
or I might actually do that a bit later
on
I think the leaves around the the middle
here these can actually pretty much stay
the same maybe the occasional gap the
idea is that the log in the middle of
the tree we don't really want to see
that you really don't want to see that
oh my goodness is 18,000 people watching
according to my would you call it the
YouTube studio thing nearly 19,000
that's crazy that's crazy
so we don't want these to be level at
the top now making one tree is one thing
right but making many of these trees
that's where it starts to get a little
bit painful you know what actually
talking it through on a live stream
makes it somewhat harder for me to be
honest with you like the the whole like
when I normally like live stream I don't
think about it I just I build and I
mainly listen to my my audiobooks or
podcast or whatever it is I'm um I'm
listening to and I made me focus on that
and then my sort of minecraft autopilot
takes over and I just I go I just go
ahead now remember we haven't taken a
step back yet to look at this and we
have no idea if this is gonna look right
or not yet at all so I have a feeling
it's probably going to be a little bit
unbalanced is how I describe building
sometimes when when when when me and
Isco were looking at this thing
he made this concept and then I copied
it over and then I kind of built on that
a bit more and I wasn't staring at it
for a good hour and I was like it's
still unbalanced it's totally unbalanced
and he was like I don't understand and I
was like when you were when he had been
eating minecraft building he yeah you
just you learn these terms and that's
where that giant gray pillar came in I
was like boom that solved the problem
you know what that's not bad for you
know it obviously needs a bit of
tweaking at the top it actually looks
like it's a little bit on the short side
now I believe I think we need to go up
to about there and sort of stretch the
whole thing up on the whole though not
bad for their first attempt of just
randomly placing them I think we've
rather oh there we go they're not a nice
shape there so let's erm you know I'm
just gonna land I'm just gonna take the
easy landing cuz we brought it we gonna
extend this up anyway so might as well
do that nice and uniform probably to
about here
and then up we go again there we go
lots of it a donation saying and
appreciate your effort and lots of hello
Green someone this had bananas that that
still are a hundred that was a that was
mumbos I think probably biggest and
failure I think being a mole
it was absolutely hilarious though
goodness oh we definitely chose the
wrong man for the job there so let's
also mix in some of these birch leaves
just to try and give it a bit more
texture that's something you can do at
custom trees that will infinitely
improve the look of your trees is just
mixing it in because you see like this
all kind of looks the same but if I
change that to birch it kind of just
breaks it up the pattern a little bit
and it helps though this is where I wish
I could fly you know this is where
creative mode comes in handy because I'm
probably gonna have to yeah add a little
bit here maybe bring this out a little
bit more because obviously that see this
is what I mean this is uniform versus a
bit more randomly placed so yeah this
kind of shows like how I'm gonna have to
I'm gonna break a few of these and add a
few in probably gonna have to make this
just a touch wider down the bottom
in order to in order to get this to have
the perfect shape all the way up the top
oh we got we got a donation from and a
crawl who says a fellow Egyptian cat
Egyptian male cat owner wanting to show
some support My partner and I watch your
home and craft episode in the evening
and have a good old laugh keep up the
good work
oh that's that's wonderful that uh if he
is she so this person obviously has the
same breed cat as myself so Maui and
pearl are a Egyptian Mau and they're
absolutely gorgeous cats I haven't met a
bad-looking now you know so these these
cats are intelligent they are they are
beautiful they are clean and they are
full of charisma and they're also quite
rare they're very they're like pedigree
and they're they're just really nice
they're snuggly cats haven't got a bad
bone in their body so they make
excellent excellent house pets or you
know house cats sorry unfortunately Mike
at the moment I'll the the tiny tiny
little one she's been sick a bit
recently so she's got to go to the vet
very soon she's but yeah she's kind of
been sick and we've tried you know
changing her food up she's quite happy
she's like still perky and yesterday
right so we were recording building this
because this was only made yesterday a
very long day it was as well and my cat
it was on my desk and all I hear is this
no no no and I'm kind of like I don't
know whether to keep recording grab the
cat stop her throwing up what do I do
I just panic and shout and she gets
scared and runs across my desk and as
she was running across the desk she
threw up she I should have just let I
should have just let her be because
there was sick all over my desk and I
had to yeah I'd to take a quick break to
you know deal with the horrible
what's really awful really really awful
but yeah I cleaned it up she's
absolutely fine
like she's absolutely okay but she's
yeah unfortunately a little under the
weather in that regard but you know I
looked it up as well obviously I've been
to the vet now as well got some some
special food to try on and also also I
think like this tree I'm you don't want
to overwork the trees either but yeah
she's absolutely fine just need to keep
a good eye on her I need to keep an eye
on OHS now people are saying cool green
in my own stream you do know that I'm
green right you don't I don't I don't
need to call green all right so I think
this has got to go as well like I didn't
really plan to too far ahead so I think
all of this maybe needs to be the same
level which means a lot of grinding out
here I think Eskow just pop this down
and perhaps didn't think too much about
the terrain so it's a it's not a big
deal this is one layer above I don't
think yes yeah I guess I can just shave
all of this I'm just thinking because
like it's a delicate operation here now
I've got to make a big fountain in the
middle here at some point and that's
yeah that's gonna be a bit of a
challenge actually so I'm not entirely
sure so you know that like Concorde
they've got their Concorde Plaza it's
got the branding the Concorde branding
and everything like yeah we're gonna
we're gonna make a bigger fountain
because Sahara we're bigger we're a
bigger name bigger brand okay better
shop i I think honk or are secretly
shaking in their boots they keep they
keep just insulting us you know saying
like inferior product or whatever
inferior product well I think they're
just scared I don't want the server to
lag so I'd better take care of this all
of this and yeah this is like I'm just
trying to wonder maybe we should mark
out where this path is gonna go as well
so maybe I'm just thinking I'm just
thinking we can hmm so I've been using
the stone brick here and I'm thinking we
just continue it it's not the most
exciting path block but hear me out I
don't want a brightly colored path block
because I want the focus to be on this
oh wow we need to fill that in that's
not meant to be like that I mean yeah we
spent a long time and obviously plenty
of building mistakes were made
let's just pop some of this stuff away
cuz I don't think I'm gonna need all
this oh no I better keep a stream torch
hmm now remind me not to place that down
I can't lose that apparently it's a
tradition although nobody told me nobody
told me there was a stream torch or
anything so Oh anyway what are we what
do we think of this tree oh it's
definitely from this angle from this
angle it's not shaped correctly at all
it looks it looks very messy it needs
move it a bit more uniform especially on
this side but I think from the front I
kind of nailed it although I haven't
actually checked
let's take a look quick look yeah it's
got a bit missing there we're gonna have
to try and reshape this oh it's actually
such a pain but hopefully once I get one
tree done it'll be easier to replicate
this over that's generally the case once
you've done one and mold it should be
fairly easy you hear that lots of mobs
going on so a lot of this stuff that
we've got to build am sahara at the
moment it's like chaw stuff I mean I've
got a lot of the chore jobs at the
moment those guys are gonna be working
on the redstone I keep saying to them
that they should just you know tell me
what to do and I'm you know I can place
redstone right I made a melon farm no I
didn't I made a pumpkin farm I mean I
made a carrot farm
I might have copied someone's design but
I made it I need just need to be told
where to place stuff you know
okay right let's this is gonna be tough
because this is where normally if I was
flying well you know had creative mode I
lean back take a look and then go and
place another one but that's a very
inefficient way of placing the blocks
this is going to be a really tough one
and I also thought I I quite naively
thought I had enough leaves for two or
three trees I haven't got enough leaves
for one tree let's take a little fly
back oh come on come on Winx come up
there there we go still not perfect
we've got a we gotta fix this up the top
here this isn't good you know what I
don't I think I probably should have
taken some full damage there but I
didn't I think maybe the server took
graze on me I don't know this might need
to be a touch higher a little bit it's
really tough when you start getting into
the sort of the really thin parts that's
where it starts getting a little bit
trickier when we bring this up take
another step back take a look yeah
that's starting to get there it's
starting to shape up a lot more I think
probably just a couple blocks here maybe
a 1-man it sound it looks like that
every single leaf block has a reason to
be placed where it is that's not the
case at all
I'm totally winging it I really I even
made a tree like this in a really long
time so it's it's yeah it's gonna be a
bit trial and error yeah I'm not gonna
overdo it too much I think that's pretty
good
I'm actually probably gonna remove just
there's a problem here and I think the
issue is probably move that and then
I'll leave it at that I'm not gonna
over-engineer it I'm not gonna overthink
it these things are just like
decorations that if you're looking too
much at the trees see you almost don't
want to beautiful trees otherwise
everyone's gonna be looking at that
rather than Sahara so I'm thinking maybe
we can add a couple of flowers around at
the bottom just to give it a bit of like
nice garden feel and then yeah you can
see why like adding some long grass and
some small flowers on this would like
give it that pop of color but you know
what that's not bad that's really not
bad it's got a nice shape it looks
natural but not too you know not to put
together not too would you quit
choreographed I guess like and then yeah
we can do this all over again except I
don't have to leave so we're not going
to and I'm pretty sure I'm all treed out
anyway now where did this where did this
go up to did it go there just there now
there's you know what's baffling to me
is that there's 20,000 people watching
me build a Minecraft tree all right
that's 20,000 people I could just place
a sapling and then there'd be 20,000
people watching me place a sapling
all right let's carry on with our chores
shall we we've got a lot to get through
so maybe we do a little bit of
everything we've done a tree we've plied
some flowers I reckon if Jack and the
spacing on that still isn't enough cuz
imagine that with the the leaves the
leaves there I reckon that needs to be
over a little bit as well so yeah
probably a good idea we leave that for
now let's mark out some of this
courtyard area and then we'll start
doing a little bit on the back and where
did I put this is just like my base
where do I put all my stuff oh not bad
you know what I haven't heard any
minecraft music yet but the music's
there none none no music we could go and
actually do you know what let's go and
splash some cash because the minecraft
music isn't happening for some reason so
[Music]
what we should do is play our own play
our own music so I got jukebox lets
going buy some music discs as some of
our favorite music discs and then we'll
actually play our own minecraft music to
build to because it doesn't seem to be
popping up I don't know we've been
streaming what that way I don't even
know how long I've been streaming for 34
minutes now and no minecraft music which
is a real shame I don't know why it's
not playing but there's a music shop
somewhere down here mmm this one did I
hit nope
I always get lost in here is it around
the corner music there we go right let's
take some votes oops let's not ruin
someone shop let's get rid of these okay
so we got more let's let's just go
through I can't even remember what most
of these sound like let's see let's put
that up a little bit to put 19% just
like just gently in the background
alright it's kind of mellow
that's a chirp chirp
[Music]
oh hey hey donated 28-pound saying too
much the same one message but thank you
green for what you do
thank you so much for the donation
that's that's really really kind of you
far let's take a look at far mmm that's
a negative
blocks oh oh oh
sold on the blocks how much you won
diamond yeah we'll have the blocks where
did it go guys
oh how whoa I'm pretty sure that popped
out of there and magicked over that was
weird
you know what we're gonna put that
upside down but anyone even knows anyway
let's have a let's have a little look at
Ward isn't that it starts off scary but
then it's kind of nice I think oh yeah
I'm not supposed to put the money in
here there's not the right vibe thirteen
now that's like the og is it that's
pretty sure thirteen was one of the
original now there's the scary one we
don't need to be known to buy that one
mmm not feeling it wait yeah that's that
that's one we'll get one of those we'll
get one of those how much are they three
diamonds one two three and Strad that'll
do for the music yeah we'll have we'll
have one of these then we'll have one of
these and we got alright we got our own
minecraft music got a take we've got to
take these matters into our own hands I
think I'm not going to spend any more on
minecraft music this is this is like my
replacement for audiobooks minecraft
jukebox you know what I just because I
haven't really heard these songs in so
long so long anyway right
go on then let's let's hear it guys so
what are we what are we gonna have we
have we've got Strad wait and blocks so
let's let's hear it in the in the old
comments here or the the chat let's see
what you eat what you want oh I don't
even remember their names you know what
white blue
red white blue or red let's let's hear
it and then we'll pop we'll pop one of
them on so someone said how long do it
Kraft sessions last if you mean the live
stream this particular live stream will
last another power and twenty I guess or
but they last two hours these like live
stream days I guess I mean this is my
first time doing this but like if you
mean just how long does a session on
minecraft last yesterday oh I'm hearing
I'm seeing a lot of reds yeah we're
gonna get red guys we're gonna go red
here first but if you mean like just on
hermitcraft in general it can last a
reit like me mumbo nice guy were playing
minecraft for about nine hours yesterday
I was admittedly I was doing another
video and hermitcraft but like I didn't
get any videos done I didn't get any
videos done at all but I still spent the
whole day on minecraft so sessions are
as long as they need to be basically
once the once the video is done the
video is done and why did I bring a
jukebox if I'm just gonna walk away from
it there we go whoo Dandan there this is
how you mind with jukebox by your side
the jukebox is highly underrated sounds
a bit off or something like almost like
- and playing at the same time right I
reckon what we should do is try and plan
out some of the pathing here I don't
know if this building is temporary or
not it's guys that you're alone I could
ask him but I don't know if that's
staying or going I think it's a
temporary place to do to do business
obviously Sahara is a start-up company
so we've still got like a long way to go
concorde have been going you know this
this entire season they've been going
and we've already made this giant
headquarters in like a couple of days
come on we I think we all know who the
superior company is I don't think I'm so
impatient I don't think I've actually
listened to these more the way through
not me just like I don't know I'm one of
those people they find listening to
music I rarely listen to the whole song
I listen to it for a bit I hit the
chorus and then I go to a new something
I'm seem really really impatient
alright listen right let's take a little
fly up and see actually we could
probably purge yourself up
if like you know for someone that's like
oh yeah I forgot about this that's where
all my stuff's gone now it's just well
hmm left the jukebox
but anyway so let's take a look so
actually this could end up being just a
straight a straight path here you can
just hear it you could just hear it but
that's where that like the interface is
gonna be like the main shop so this
actually makes a lot of sense just to go
straight to that shop and then I guess
we have decoration there I don't I don't
know I we didn't really plan that far
ahead
hmm another thing that throws a spanner
in the works is this is the train
station this is like squeeze we might
need to like shrink that down a little
bit scars building that's a hopefully
scar we can work with him to make that a
little bit smaller hmm I'm trying to
think cuz I mean I could send them on a
wild goose chase it could go around the
back I mean I could make this path go
out here but the reality is you're
probably just gonna take the shortest
route I think it should probably just go
straight to be honest with you I think
that's probably the easiest easiest
thing to do and I think as for design of
this part of the building absolutely no
I don't think any of us have even
thought that far the Redstone may be
they've got some big plans for that but
as for the design of the building
they're probably gonna leave that to me
I imagine
I usually start out by making some
pretty awful drawings in ms paint or
something put it together it helps just
to sketch out because you know placing
blocks in a line especially in survival
it's very very time-consuming so you
know I can draw a really powerful
picture in Photoshop or pain in you know
two seconds to actually build a
prototype I want to fill this in this is
probably why we have such a mob problem
this for a while so just a regular dudes
they $35 thank you very much very
generous so people are saying the torch
has the wrong date on it no oh it does
23:02 it's not February you know that
the evidence is there I'm gonna have to
rename this that's embarrassing they
come and scar handed me this torch right
and they said take care of this torch
it's very important oh so they told me
to look after that torch and I
immediately ruined it
listen let's fix the date shall we let's
fix the date - so it is the 23rd of
March 2019 there we go streamed a torch
fixed and what I did was I just I put it
down on the floor yeah I put it down the
floor picked it straight back up and it
obviously vanished and became a regular
sort Jen but don't worry it's exactly
the same torch and it's actually got the
right date on it this time and this is
how we do the date in the UK by the way
it's day month year it makes the most
sense we don't put the month first
that never made sense to me all right
let's continue we've got a lot of laying
out to do we've got a lot of chores to
do when it comes to this sort of
building and this is the sort thing I
would never normally record so you know
you're getting a bit of an insight here
into how how I how I do things for my
videos like this is the sort of thing I
would never record it's just got to be
done
I might time lapse it at most at most I
might time that's it right so let's
assume that this path is gonna go all
the way here as a directive route it's
not actually how I pictured it but it
actually makes the most sense probably
doesn't need this in here either
that's unfortunate we've got as you
might leave that there simply because
this is the rail track which we might
actually do but I've I filled that in I
spent a bit of time filling that in the
thing is the the train stations right
there and so like that train track was
gonna cut straight through our building
and Ren agreed that it could go
underground as long as there was a glass
top so compromise found right there Ben
Smith's donated to Palace said not much
but keep up the good work you know I'm
very grateful that you're even watching
so thank you very very much it's really
really appreciated oh we need we need a
new we need new music we need a new
music music has stopped we need more we
need more jukebox right let's take pop
that out and yeah I'm surprised they
haven't added more music discs it's been
a while how come we keep leaving now
where my stone
actually I could just craft something so
lazy that's let's just bring one of
these crafting tables over here oh I
know this one yeah actually no this one
a bit better you guys are gonna have to
warn me when it's nearly time for friend
to come on by the way cuz I'm deaf so
I'm thinking we do this
junk in my factory all the time
so I'm thinking maybe we do something
like this just to give it a bit of a
pattern of some kind
[Music]
it's always I have to sacrifice
something in my inventory all the time
because of this it's put the diamonds
away you know what we're actually
running low on diamonds again but that
money that I got from scar has been
reinvested into making this like it
sometimes it's just quicker you've seen
how long it took me to build that tree
like it sometimes it's just much easier
to just buy the materials that you need
you know actually that's we're just
gonna do this so yeah ivory invested all
of my diamonds and I finished all of my
did you die boxes so maybe when we hand
over the stream day torch we can try and
sell a box to Reyn see if he wants one
because I need to basically target the
people that die the most on the server
and one of them is me so I can't resell
one to myself cuz I can't even afford my
own did you dye boxes but I think Ren is
rich from the lock shop scar definitely
could I hope that he actually found
found it to have good use I probably
should try and sell one to mumbo he's
also a pretty high def count
we'll see we'll see who else really like
dies a lot of the server
[Music]
you know this is a really chill one by
this I again I think I don't fit I don't
think I've ever listened this far into
it it gets more chill can you believe
that minecraft is nearly two years old
that's mad to me yeah it's a little bit
dull I think this walkway just the stone
stone brick maybe but like I said I kind
of want it I could add a couple of
little things to improve it I don't
really want to have any scrap stone
brick in here because it will make it
look like Sahara isn't brand new which
is definitely not what we want we wanted
to seem about as new as it gets we need
it we need a parrot on the jukebox Ryan
wait wait fear donated 10 and said we
need a parrot on the jukebox you know
what you are so unbelievably correct
we're gonna take a good minute out of
our time to bring over one of our trusty
verbs I'm not sure if this is gonna work
it took me ages to get the birds in from
from the jungle to hear in the first
place
well did you see that little lag spike
where's we're sorry
I'm sorry should be well he should be
there it there is there is all right so
I believe that he should you see that's
why I'm the best liar on the server
he should teleport to me I believe there
is okay so if I go down here there we go
oh man I love maybe we'll do some
acrobatics later embarrass myself
because I've got an audience right I
should be in the same chunk as the bird
yeah there is where are you going
yeah get get back here okay we can head
back over to the jukebox and started all
over again
I should have brought bought more than
three discs I feel for sure all right
I think I think we're safe now I think
we could go all the way back to the box
oh do you see that little bit of lag
there little bit like ah the song
finished well I've only got one more to
play where are you
can you pop over here yeah come on come
on you know but that'll do well place
one yeah yes yes
[Music]
shake it why is that so funny is that
the only dance that they do that's
that's a pretty good imitation of what
how I danced in real life as well let's
carry on I should have brought all of
the birds I should have brought all of
the birds with me
[Music]
that's just making this path all the
better all the better
I love Minecraft little little quirks
quirks like that I wish I brought more
and more music discs with me I think
that's all we've got basically if I it
trust me if I had a face camera so I
would I would dance I would dance just
like that probably in time as well are
you saying upside down staircases and
then you waterlog them is that is that
what you're saying
does that give a different color because
I thought the water just appeared on the
top I might I might be about to be
taught something that I wasn't fully
aware of I've met we don't have a bucket
here I'm gonna have to make one if this
is a thing this could be revolutionary
for detailing could be revolutionary
it needs some water we're gonna go for a
swoop down come on there we go server no
that was a fail as a failure you need to
like youth like skin the top and then
take the water
right let's find out if this is a this
is got some merit I see no color
variance so maybe I'm misunderstanding I
and I don't see any color variants there
at all am i misunderstanding I mean I
even had the wrong block for a star so
unless unless they literally meant like
that and then have water along the edge
in which case that could be really
interesting because I could add water
all the way along and it could even feed
into a fountain over there that's not a
bad idea I guess I totally misunderstood
that
so yeah the more obvious thing of course
was to put it on the edge there I got
really hype with that I thought it might
actually make the stone brick like look
a little bit damp as if it was wet or
something that that's actually would be
really cool you know slightly darker
stone brick you could you could use that
I'm pretty sure is it possible to make a
redstone jukebox is that what you're
saying like all I could have a jukebox
in there you say oh yeah I could
actually I could move the jukebox up
into my like mini jungle that's for sure
you know what there's only a little bit
left just gonna play some stairs there
we go right that little chores done
you're not dancing does he dance if he's
on your shoulder right well I I wish I'd
bought more now but I guess we'll go
back to this one
why isn't he going on my shoulder if he
flies and waddles
why isn't he why only dancing
why aren't you dancing I can't believe
he flies and waddles gone go back oh
there we go I picked him up he doesn't
dance on the shoulder or do I have to
restart it
let's try risk oh that's really
disappointing I'm disappointed in you
burb I am disappointed I am very very
disappointed in you I thought they did
why is he decided these doesn't want to
easy or danced out all right hope you
get it's not dancing anymore
huh that's alright I don't think I can
dance for either even that's kind of sad
that's kind of sad anyway we keep
getting distracted by the birds I think
maybe we should try and like what's out
The Fountains gonna go that's gonna be
very up we go
needs more height
I don't have a slow falling potion
before you'll tell me that I need a slow
falling potion okay okay okay
I'd you know what I want desperately on
the server is someone to make a flying
course a proper a really nice flying
course videos keep up the good work and
well yeah they are pills a little bit
sick you missed it earlier but oh my
goodness there's 25,000 people watching
that's got to be a record that's
unbelievable
you're watching me in my parrot Jam and
we're just all we're doing is placing
some smooth grass at Sahara you know
what yeah I'm getting a little bit burnt
out on this I want to I want to try and
just do small things so it looks like
we're doing a lot but in reality we're
we're not actually committing and
finishing any one thing so what we're
gonna do is we're just gonna place a
little bit of this and then we're gonna
go and work on the back of the Sahara
thing there
crazy for a day donates a ten-pound
saying gran I love that you'll put your
time and effort into these videos and
thank you for your work
oh well thank you very much for donating
but you know this is it it is really is
a is a very very fun job to do so you
know it is a lot of time and effort but
you know a lot of people also do this
job they you know they all put their
time and effort into this why was I
saving all of this grass off when it's
probably gonna be grass anyway hmm let's
take the cobblestone find the midpoint
roughly that's too long that's too
that's too long to count I'm gonna lose
it
let's just guess to me it's guess to me
[Music]
mm-hmm there we go that's probably about
right if it's not I'll shift it around
but if that's we may also want to try
and send to this approximately with
in the center this guesstimate again
around here
I want to put a giant a of course in the
middle of the fountain
so let's guesstimate the size
and probably estimate guesstimate this
is how I build those maybe guesstimate
probably around that sort of size now
that's one two three four five six seven
we may be we may be way off here one two
three four five six
baby wails see since I'm thinking that
the fountain goes here around that
guestimation and we have a giant a
architect logo and since then since
we're passing on the torch to rented a
day we should probably probably do
something probably set something up
not sure what though I want to sell him
and did you die box that's the problem
I need his money I need his his diamonds
I could I could I could but I could
barter the the stream torch I'm not
gonna pass him the torch until he paid
he buys one of mine did you dive boxes
[Music]
hopefully we'll take a step back and
find out if this is even remotely
correct the mobs have started pouring in
or was actually there's one creeper one
skeleton they're gonna trust me this
place is an absolute nightmare it's not
worth why did I just fly into a wall all
right we're going in here I heard it I
heard it blew up my bed at the same time
oh this is when you need a did you die
box right let's see if we can get back
oh that's terrible
at least it's daytime so it won't be a
big problem problem did you guys see him
cuz I definitely didn't see that creeper
I was looking out I was looking out
oh man that's really bad hmm
this way question mark well that's not
very helpful all that looks like the
right way
when in doubt follow the black concrete
Oh is that minecraft music or is that
nether music now that might be the music
of the nether I just realized what
Sahara dude this is really spooky
minecraft music when did when in
Minecraft gets spooky I don't like this
at all we need to get out of here okay I
know if you guys can hear that anyway
what's a horror really needs that I did
not think about one bit
we need another portal we absolutely
need another portal and it would go
somewhere here let's pop into this one
shall we
I've completely forgot I'm like planning
out all of the rooms in my in my head
but I didn't consider that kind of far
away I kind of wanted to to commandeer
one of horses but I'll be fine fine oh
there we go oh there we go we go soon we
got some nice alpha music coming through
here that's nice I like that I can't
believe that guys honestly I did not see
that creeper one bit one bit it's bound
to happen
I think I'm not even top of the death
list though like I think you know the
server keeps count of how many times
you've died you know once we get our
stuff back we're gonna find out please
tell me there's nothing more bit of bit
of damage not a problem
easy to fix
I love the music here we go
believable actually what I mean to say
is totally at least the parents alright
let's get rid of all this junk forever
collecting collecting jug right so let's
do tool check we've got two pickaxes we
got the shovel we got the axe
it's always the tridon there we go
try it in check I tell you what guys I'm
not losing another Trident it's
absolutely ridiculous how many tries
I've missed there we go problem solved
and you know what we're gonna place down
some more torches dear we're gonna need
some more white concrete you know that's
probably a good time to start working on
the back of this whole thing let's go
should we bring the jukebox with us it's
been it's been pretty Pleasant actually
having the jukebox will bring we'll
bring our e in the jukebox with us since
that's it's been useful oh that's a
surprisingly tough to break of course
I've got just sacrificed some stuff
don't need the bucket
probably can do that sticks there we go
right come on you let's uh actually
let's just take a look at what this
looks like I didn't actually check this
placement at all there we go yeah I
think we might want to actually send to
this I know that here's the thing guys
so this lets actually purge our selves
up on here so I can explain what the
problem is here so right it looks
slightly too far to the right at the
moment at the moment that's the problem
okay so it should be about there if I
want it to be centered but and here's
the thing I really don't want to
encroach too much on TFC space so we may
create a small wall just to make sure
that we separate and like make sure we
we don't intrude on anything going on
over there
sorry buddy come on right so we don't
want to intrude so we might build a
small wall just to make sure we define
our area much better so maybe along here
that then makes that more centered so or
we could send to this whole space but
then it might encroach over there
so it might be in the right space I
think it does need to shift a little bit
hmm thinking emoji alright let's let's
go to the back of the base here and get
ourselves set up so there's not like I
said earlier not a lot of thought has
gone into this too much
I suppose do you know what I didn't do
guys I didn't I didn't I didn't actually
change the title this is how terrible of
a streamer there's there's 20 there's
24,000 people watching a stream by Green
who has nearly 3 million subscribers who
forgot to put the title of the stream in
it just says hermitcraft 6 live that's
it it doesn't have a title oh my
goodness hold on I need to change the
title I'm gonna call the title cool
green no no I'm gonna call it working on
Sahara because that's what we've been
doing and hopefully does that say but I
guess it just saves butt so there's no
save button oh well if you refresh it
maybe it'll work
ok so let's think about this logically
we need to create a lot of rooms here so
that's all red stone behind there that's
all red stone and this is gonna be the
little courtyard so I think this might
need to be dug out which is frustrating
if we got re with where's the bird gone
the bird is missing and the bird is
definitely missing well ill TP to us so
these mobs how has he seen me from all
the way over there is that normal how
much vision do these guys have no that
was a terrible shot bad well that went
straight through him I didn't even miss
that one but don't want any of this
these guys are tough there we go oh
there you are
right so I think maybe we should start
up there and make it make this as big as
we need I think there should be a little
overhang here so this could come out see
this is where it gets complicated so I
want to utilize this space as much as
possible and to be fair I could put
anything I need to underground as well
underground as well hmm
oh my goodness oh my goodness the back
packing trombonist has had a genius idea
you should put a did you die satellite
store on spawn Island so if you die
properly lose your bed everything you
can buy something there I could I could
actually do that I could do that that's
a really smart thing to do I'll get some
sales from there for sure all right
let's just start let's just start
building sometimes you just got a crack
on with it I just need to remember to
light it up otherwise we're gonna just
contribute even further to this horrible
mob problem our let's torches oh we need
some right come on then come on in chat
red blue or white let me know and then
we'll pop the jukebox on where's the
bird is it areas
all right let's pop you down
let's see so yeah I think we want to I
don't know why this is here maybe maybe
it's gone mom loaded that but I need to
make sure that I actually have enough
space I'm thinking like the conference
room needs to go in here so we need to
we need to make sure we leave enough
space like we've got big plans for
siharan it's it's gonna be so much more
than just a place where you buy stuff
okay it's more than a shop it really is
gonna be more than a shot this is gonna
be the likes of which hermit craft and
probably minecraft has never seen they
the amount of the amount of things the
Sahara is going to be doing in order to
sell some sand shall we say it's going
to be absolutely insane and I can't wait
for you guys to see it I'm kind of
bummed out that you guys didn't get to
see my episode on all of this before the
livestream today it's just the way
things worked out the videos not done
ever literally everyone is uploading on
Sunday it's just you know the stream
they landed on Saturday in an ideal
world stream day would have been Sunday
and then upload day would have been wait
yes I all right white disk white disk
blue disk okay let's go blue disk shall
we
there there we go they don't just hold
him does do they only danced a certain
disks
no no they dance to all of them all
right we're good we'll go to we'll go
blue disc for you I don't think that I
don't think that's ever gonna get old
I'm getting so many cool Mambo spam
please don't spam I'm not calling Mambo
because he's not even there so forget it
please don't spam you know what the G
box really does listen this is me on of
this is me on my Saturday night guys
[Music]
only 45 minutes left for today's stream
I think what we'll do we'll do this for
15 minutes and then we're gonna go and
I'm just looking inside
cap the submissive we can't all be as
wholesome as that parent
[Music]
I gotta say guys thank you so much for
all the donations that you guys are
sending through it really does make
doing these live streams worthwhile
because normally I would just basically
spend my time you know I'd spend the
hours doing this into a time lapse or
something but you know with with the
donations it makes it totally feasible
to do this on stream which you know it's
really not something I'm used to
streaming is still a bit of a odd
concept to me so yeah I really really
appreciate the support it kind of yeah I
don't know I just I really appreciate it
I don't know else to say thank you thank
you oh man I don't even know how far out
I want to go here maybe this is about as
far because I want this to overhang a
bit and that's probably big enough for a
conference room so I'm thinking this is
probably the place to stop which means
all this has got a gun not sure where
all this came from anyway I'm pretty
sure also we want a want a courtyard
here
think I think Sahar is also gonna need
like a secret our R&D research and
development facility we need like some
racing like major major Sahara secrets
and like as as a fan you guys gotta keep
your keep your silencer fill this in
that's one of the things that's easy to
forget filling in like it's very easy
just to leave this small stuff keep keep
hearing zombies but it's just this guy
jamming out doing some zombie noises
there we go
[Music]
four Rockets oh yeah did I leave the bed
I left the bed out here let's see if I
can nope sometimes I really suck at
flying Helena said spawn Island store
should be called the oh oh no fool me
once fool me once you know what that was
really scary because I was actually
reading out a donation and I saw it not
on my game but on the tiny little screen
that I have for obs
and I saw it in like what you guys see
on the stream right oh no no no no no no
no dear wait okay so there's clearly a
bit of a torch problem around here so
let's just let's just overdo it maybe
with the torches get rid of this problem
altogether I still got the streamed a
torch we'll leave that up there let's
get rid of so much junk as well there we
go that's that's the Flying Eye no see
oh my god I'm gonna need more torches
why is this girl it's girl you've missed
a bit I haven't actually got any more
torches which is a bit of a bummer the
music stopped why are you still jamming
also me on a Friday night will there be
a Sahara cafeteria that would be a
really smart place to like sell some
food I think but I don't think so I
really want every room that we create in
Sahara to have
a purpose and by purpose I don't just
mean like the meeting room I wanted to
actually be used in videos or in other
people's content and I don't really want
to spoil it especially in an industry my
the rooms that I'm gonna create for
Sahara they are they are tip-top secret
at the moment so we've got to keep it to
ourselves
now that is a very awkward gap there I
guess we'll just see probably best just
extend them unless we actually accept I
think maybe we should extend black yeah
forget this a lot of this has been built
on just a total win the rest of its been
planned out so there's like bits like
here that haven't been thought through
but still look okay I reckon in order
for this to look
perfect
[Music]
it's just extend this out
yeah I reckon about it and then that way
they can stay exactly where it is I'm
probably gonna run out of white concrete
but that's okay cuz we've only got 20
more minutes and then we're gonna go
call someone yeah I'm out of like
concrete please tell me there's some
just around we could go on a little
flying spree actually that's always fun
I like I like to fly around the shopping
district right check check check not in
the mood the amount of concrete we've
had to grind out for this project is
absolutely the same there we go
ah there we go Jack there's always a bit
lying around you know what we've had you
made some progress but it's been two
hours I know we messed around with the
parrot but like we've we've made that
and we made a tree and yeah that's about
it you haven't done a lot
we added some carpets up here that's
kind of gonna give you a little bit of
an idea of how long this build has taken
so far I mean I think we built four I
think we started recording about 3:00
p.m. and we didn't finish till late
easily six hours of building with three
people that's that's quite that's quite
impressive and a song yeah so what we
can do is just connect this up and then
that should be it for so the dimensions
of this room I don't know quite how this
is all gonna connect up here because
obviously this room has got to flow into
that yeah this is the bit that we
haven't thought through at all did we do
blue or red I think we'd there we go
yeah you keep jamming you keep jamming
probably need to extend this over just
connect it up probably best not to have
these random gaps everywhere
[Music]
hey guys I'm gonna go home
oh you cheeky Skelly
I can't I can't really see consuming it
oh my cats are so Maui and pearl right
now are playing a game called I'll chase
you and then you chase me it's their
favorite game to play they absolutely
love it all right we're gonna need some
torches not that torch we're gonna go
make some more cuz yeah this girl's
probably gonna rip my head off if I
leave this place to spawn more mobs
there's got to be torturous as well
we've basically got everything we need
but we keep like just putting it all in
random chests there's got to be some
tiny bit of calm there's some cold you
know I can take it from there problem
solved problem solved seven minutes
until the mischeif is happening so guys
I need to I need ideas I don't know what
I'm doing everywhere left for one second
get go downtown there we go I don't even
want to deal with these guys right I
need some ideas mischief mischief
mischief I'll tell you what we could do
and this is them I guess it's a stupid
but I want to promote suhara
preemptively like yeah you know what we
can't do that
we can't actually promote suhara until
we've actually got something to sell so
we'll might have to leave that for now
I'm just gonna say what we could do is
put some signs outside all the con Corp
shops saying like shop at Sahara but
there's no point because you can't shop
at Sahara yeah and that's kind of what
they've got over us at the moment the
fact that they've got shops and
retailers
busy devilish that's what I was devilish
yeah we can definitely I can't wait to
get all of this Sahara stuff underway
it's gonna be amazing
[Music]
I need to
I need to picking that up but I can't
this angle all these mobs I understand
why a Scouts annoyed me now I really do
[Music]
isn't seen yet off you go
okay so there's gonna be enough space
for a room down here enough room space
for a room up there oh there's more than
enough space for a room here a little
plenty of space
absolutely plenty of space don't know
what we're gonna do you know what would
be really cool kind of what they do in
really fancy places is they kind of have
like exposed rocks all the way up here
like I could have have it like you know
but it's almost like the inside of a
cave or whatever like we have kept we've
kept the original details but
so how big do I want this room fairly
big Oh
[Music]
oops let's get rid of that let's put the
music down cuz we got the jukebox still
running anyway what was I gonna look I
was gonna look up deaths how many times
have I died die death death death death
here's a crazy statistic for you he is a
crazy statistic so since last death 23
minutes per time cept in a bed 600 where
am I looking
number of deaths a hundred and thirty
nine that's pretty impressive but it's
not the worst on the server what I was
looking for his time played it was
something like 34 days which is crazy
but I can't seem to find it I've spent
one point four days of my life sneaking
sneaking in minecraft yeah it's nearly
35 days ok 35 days played just not on
minecraft but on hermitcraft in
particular so just on hermitcraft alone
I've spent 35 days that's over a month
ok now here's where it gets complicated
so over a month now the Hermit craft
server has been going for about eight
months now nearly nine months eight
hours yeah let's call it nine just in
case I'm I'm wrong with the egg so one
ninth of my entire time and that's you
know not including the time I take to
sleep and stuff has been spent on hermit
craft unbelievable amount of time has to
be spent in order to make the episodes
I'm only on episode like 56 I think I'm
probably one of the lowest you know out
of the people they're active on the
server I'm probably the furthest behind
in episode number it's just I just take
my time basically on on making making
sure that they yeah they're up to
scratch
Aiden donated and said coolbrian hi
grant I just shout green now Korean I
think it seems so quiet without the
jukebox doesn't it just heard a llama in
the background oh my goodness did I miss
a big donation at some point
I must have missed a big donation at
some point I I haven't really been
paying how much I've been focused on
trying to steer that's a problem I'm not
the best stream in the world like in
fact I'm probably one of the worst but I
don't pay attention to some of the
things that I perhaps should it says
that their darkest legend is the top
donator for 173 pounds now I must have
missed that that sounds like $200 to me
so I just want to say a huge huge huge
thank you I think I've I must have
missed it at some point oh great can't
even look at that is there no one else
dead us on the server but he's not
sleeping he probably in the nether yes I
think that's where he lives I mean this
is this this shows you earth man okay
yam Balin I'm bailing can we take off
with one rocket there we go let's see if
there's a see this is the problem this
is the problem look at all of these mobs
that is the problem we have in this area
on Sahara is just the insane amount of
mobs that's born
oh I think I just D spawned them by
flying away less embarrassing anyway
let's go and sleep and we've hit the
last half hour so it's time to cause
some mayhem let's put the building
blocks away I must admit I thought
rather rather naively I guess that I
could just carry on building where I
left off we got in such a good groove
yesterday with building we just we just
actually just got on with it and got it
done and now like when you build
something like six hours straight we
didn't break it so you know it's kind of
hard to pick up again a little bit a
little bit it's hard to just pick up
where you left off on a big session like
that kind of burnt out on it let's pop
these music discs away hmm I'm gonna
think do my best thinking when I'm
stretching Oh No yeah okay I'll tell you
what I did want to do I want to reverse
engineer that that looks like two
Pistons two observers and a couple of
slime blocks
hmmm do we even need we probably need a
power source
we'll need a piston probably sticky not
sure observer yes check done let's see
if we can fly up here this is gonna be a
tricky one oh I didn't want to flap here
all right let's get this is gonna be a
tricky one need to fly and land yeah we
made it okay okay I don't have this line
box that I need here so how does this
work so we have piston facing that way
piston facing that way an observer that
way in that way hmm so I remember that
now let's take that down we're gonna
reverse engineer this mumbo is afk mumbo
is afk I'm not sure where mumbos afk
though I was gonna say we could put him
on a flag machine and send him a million
blocks away but I'm not entirely sure
where he is and we could spend easily
over half an hour trying to find him
anyway that's hugely the blocks that we
need
I must have some at the base
although slime blocks is not my
particular strong suit I have to admit
look at how much of a mess this has
become by the way it's it's growing I
almost want this to continue growing oh
they were sticky pistons if I was sticky
no slime blocks to the blocks
ah there's one no that looks so close to
slime blocks there we got some slime
balls that'll do that will do excellent
excellent
all right I've never made one of these
before by the way this is a bit of a new
thing why they're signs they're pancakes
a yummy pancakes a yummy huh pancakes
are yummy you always find something new
on the hermit craft server there's
always something that you missed always
always always
all right so I believe that I have to
build this at least let you know
floating otherwise it's just not I'm not
gonna work
so I've already forgotten the way it
goes is it like I'm rubbish at this
don't have the thought of the support
mechanism for this all right so there
was one like that and then there was it
definitely wasn't facing down this is
this is gonna this is what it looks like
when green does wet redstone just no
idea no idea what I'm doing I'm just
copying blindly like I know that this
works because I saw it work but I don't
know how it works and I'm guessing when
I make it again ultra glitched one five
eight says hey green your imagination
has helped me in Minecraft also mumbo
jumbo you are afk he's always afk dude
always thank you very much for the
donation I really appreciate it now we
have to try and remember I didn't see
any slime blocks so it must have been
something like that I think they were
facing inwards and then I place these
are you know what I think I've nailed
this I might be speaking too soon but I
am pretty sure I've nailed this
we placed down the boat now how do we
power it that's what I want to know how
to power it
hmm maybe I don't even know I mailed it
in the wrong direction that's so
embarrassing that's like having it
having the car stuck in Reverse and then
just man that's embarrassing right yeah
okay I deserve that we have to fix this
I've never been inside here oh that's
cool
should have lit that up though sure to
let that up that's so so embarrassing so
embarrassing so I should have put I
think I know I did wrong I should have
put it on the other side I haven't even
got enough prismarine here probably this
block so embarrassing all right let's
try this
wait I don't want to ruin this please go
here clearly okay round two everybody
round two so we're gonna do the same
thing again but this time I believe what
I did wrong was I put the torch on the
wrong one because I need that piston to
go first
I need that piston to go first so think
we just we do the same thing all over
again
question mark
I don't even know why I'm doing this I
just want to practice learning how to
make these sorts of flying machines
because I know that this is gonna be
useful for me I know that one day I'm
gonna need a flying machine and even
this very simple one that mumbo made
this this is gonna this is gonna help me
I just I can feel it I can feel it in my
bones
alright so let's try it again it went
something like this and then we try
again now this goes backwards we're done
that's it we failed the mission believe
that alright boom and then this time
it's not connected to anything is it get
it there we go ha ha ha perfect that is
the sound of success
I have no idea how this is even working
I literally I literally don't understand
let me try and fathom this so no way I
totally understand so I put the torch on
the side of the observer on the right
that activates the piston which
activates it the observer on my left
which then you know activates the one on
the right again so edit because it
pushed that one piston pushed all of the
slime blocks are just sticking together
it then dragged it along and butterbean
bada-boom we have a winner you know what
I think I'm gonna go up this is the only
you know rent Ren I'm sorry bro
your your rail network is nothing
nothing compared to my boat in the sky
and I've just had an idea
you could you could make one of these
and like have checkpoints I guess
because obviously I saw mumbo with his
tea and II think back and he could
control it what if he could create like
sky lights so you basically just had
corners so we need when the machine gets
to the corner it then turns right and it
turns left
you have stations and you could blocks
ah there we go that's why that's why you
put that back where it was you know
messing with the micros ass oh no I
think Ren I think I think Ren heard us
he knows he knows what we're up to
I'm flying with extremely low FPS like
it's like it's like I'm printing across
the sky this is this is actually kind of
cool the hermit craft server is a weird
mix and a match and I think that what's
cool is that what you see here is
obviously a lot of different people's
style of building however it's actually
very representative of a lot of
Minecraft servers in general like you
know for those of the servers that
actually stay and I have a community etc
you end up with a whole diverse
catalogue of buildings and that
represents it just as much it's kind of
cool it's very very cool I don't really
know where we're going with this I guess
we're taking it all the way to Concord
Sahara is on its way to Concord and
we've only got 19 minutes left on this
stream because I could only do two hours
on this livestream day everyone has been
streaming on Liam hermit craft server
has been a pretty pretty busy day all
around and it looks like quite a lot of
stuff has been done
oh no porn Oh almost got him oh he's got
him is that coming back there it is wait
but okay I thought I thought it was
going to stuff
oh this is so cool it is very slow
though I could have flown this in about
two seconds in about two seconds
in about two seconds a lot of people are
telling me that jangula is a scowl and
just random to his and thing guys
so there's bit spoilers already for next
episode but we've already started like
investigating who the Jaguar is and
you'll find out what we found out
tomorrow in the episode but for some
reason right everyone is spamming me
telling me the random people are the
jangula I've heard that it's cows the
jangula I've heard that Cubs the
Chandler I've heard that stresses the
jangling I've heard that I'm the jangula
I mean I'm not the jangle I'm the one
trying to find out who the jungler is
well I like the jungler and I just don't
know it hmm oh wow would you look look
how beautiful that is that that is
really really cool anyway I did also say
that we would do some intense flying so
I think we should do that but I have a
question to ask everybody how do you
stop this thing that was something I
really honestly did not think about at
all at all how do you stop this thing if
I get out I think I'm gonna fall out so
I'm not gonna do that now if I break
this maybe I can't break it in time
I think this is my life now I think this
is my life
aha instant break come on how do i okay
there we go problem solved everybody
problem solved
redstone stuff super valuable so I'm
gonna fall down and get all this but
that was fun that was the neat little
project now I know how to put somebody
in a fail-safe flying machine that's
that is the simple redstone that I can
remember forever i I've always pictured
flying machines as one of these
incomprehensible bit of redstone that I
didn't understand but now I actually
kind of get it that very simple design
mind I probably wouldn't be able to
build anything much bigger than that
however there we go there's all the
blocks floating around now that I know
that we can definitely send someone off
into the infinite generation shall we
say I'm gonna go and put all of my stuff
away because I promised everyone that we
would do some intense flying around the
shopping district now intense flying
means it just means that I fly in
between things at a very high pace and I
basically spam rockets and do that now
because I'm streaming it does produce a
little bit of lag so there's there is a
chance that I'm going to hit something
and I always do hit something it just
looks like I'm in total control so
anyway we're gonna go and get some
rockets we're gonna put this stuff away
and we're gonna go fly around the
shopping district and that should lead
us i'll there's some slots there it
should lead us nicely onto handing over
the torch to Rend dog
we need a route though I need a route a
good a good strong route to take I
missed a sticky piston
oh well hmm that's not good all right
I mean inventory management's probably
my weakest weakest thing on the server
oh my god empty maps so much rubbish
everywhere alright let's get rid of all
this stuff I'm gonna need some more I'm
gonna need some more rockets for sure we
can do that at my base now guys I don't
need I don't need to
anything I don't need to buy well yeah
that's a lie
Annie I don't need to buy any rockets
anymore because I've got infinite
gunpowder or enough gunpowder to last me
a lifetime
like where is it a lot of sand I didn't
know I had that many pumpkins and I've
got infinite reeds with my Reed farm so
we take the sugarcane
I still call them reeds to this day how
weird is that if they were called reeds
when the game first came out when mike
refers came out and i still call them
reeds
all right that's so one two three one
three and we can make plenty of rockets
I don't need to buy rockets anymore I
can burn through as much as I can
without being judged anymore I could
judge so much by my flying oh no I had
Rockets all right let's get rid of this
all righty
we're probably gonna die but let's go so
here we go here we go
22,000 people about to watch some
intense flying and I'm gonna go first
person so if we get enough height we can
actually get so much we can get more
speed than if I use a rocket burn so
down we go now the hardest route that I
found is going through those trees there
but also through through here up and
around down mmm I can't quite move fast
enough sometimes Oh we had up yet as a
fall through here Oh got away with that
one it is a little bit hard with the
with the lag here because obviously I'm
streaming it's putting a lot of pretty
intense on the computer because it's
like doing four different screens but we
can get away with some cool stuff I
think I need more trees and stuff too
able to fly in and out one of the cool
things I like to do now this is not
actually that difficult because you can
just find a route but trying to fly
through here is is actually good fun
let's eat as well I love I love flies
it's one of my favorite things I don't
know what I'm gonna do when eventually
we hit season seven and I don't have my
Electra take that SpaceX Korean exits
coming this it's true Scott it is very
true I can I can weave I can go I can go
to space
I can go to space I need SpaceX that was
really nice bit to fly around Ren
because yeah he's got his dragon it's
ghost dragon right through here oh he's
got rid of that there was a little hole
there that I could fly through oh I
messed that up flying through the trees
is always difficult
ran this is the Kings this is looking
cool he's not even there he's not even
there dudes is he just he's really not
there he's he's a gonzo he's gonzo hmm
oh I finally I kept my redstone stuff we
could have sent him on a little little
journey he's got he's got sunglasses on
look at his cool dude under there he's a
tired man
under they'll do that through his eyes
oh I've got an idea got an idea
at one point in Minecraft right pushing
pushing someone on minecraft was like
super useful and annoying they removed
it you used to just like go straight
through them then they brought it back
and everyone that had played the game
since the start were like oh come on
then come on Randy you going in the
drink
if this doesn't bring him back I don't
know what will
he shouldn't be afk anyway let's be
honest he's not wearing armor he
shouldn't be afk
he needs to be taught a lesson I haven't
got any blocks so this could be
dangerous I can't even save him if I
wanted to oh well hopefully he'll learn
his lesson guys let's get some sad oh no
he's probably terraforming this let's
get some throwaway blocks nope let's
skedaddle let's get out of here
he's she shouldn't be afk gran you
should no be afk no like that that was a
delayed portal type I really I need a
better route all the skull scars not afk
mumbos FK let's go see if numbers that
is based by the way
I need to sell it did you die box thank
you so much for reminding me oh my
goodness I totally forgot about that
I've had a few donations come through
and some guys same locus is saying that
he's the jangula well I knew it of
course I knew it from the beginning of
course you're the jagneauxs so obvious
had loads of donations cover theory hey
big fan thank you very much great stream
sorry it's not much hey that honestly
just watching is absolutely amazing you
know being here to support me there's
22,000 people somehow there's 22,000
people I don't don't don't understand
right oh yeah see I was gonna pick up
one of these cuz we're gonna need to
sell one of these I checked that all of
these are full of their enchantments
yeah punch that couldn't be better it's
not bad not bad
that's perfect perfect perfect all bane
of arthropods that's not a great sort of
let's swap that out they're not all the
same they're not exactly the same I
didn't even put the sword in that one we
need to get our sail together we need to
get our sales pitch and you get a sales
pitch okay right hmm all right good luck
get a look in the mirror you can look in
the mirror hello Brandon bye boxes that
should do it
that should do it that's a good sales
pitch that's a that's a brilliant sales
pitch that's all we need basically
anyway I was wondering like for my base
I'm not really happy with like the
layers so the big thing about my base is
like it's pretty iconic it's got a
really nice like it's like kind of like
a landmark in a way in its size but a
lot of its wasted I was gonna move my
storage system up here but that never
happened and it's probably not going to
happen as well
it's probably not gonna happen because
this is this is my jam this is me this
is me all
but these bits up here this one in
particular has absolutely nothing in it
and I don't know what's put in it
I can't change my skin at the moment I
want to put the bowtie on but that would
require me logging which is so
frustrating
anyway I could I could see better hold
on I'm gonna I'm gonna see if I can
change my skin real quick I can pretty
sure I can put the bowtie on not gonna
be a big deal just give me a second we
got if we got to do the sales pitch
we've got to do it properly guys got to
do it properly mmm bowtie bowtie Korean
areas boom now hopefully if we
disconnect and we log back here
oh of course of course give me a second
guys
it's just gonna be a black blank screen
for half a second oh I need to restart
the launcher as well I've really that
that is one of the things that really
annoys me is basically every time every
time you've got to do this one of the
really annoying things is just invalid
session really annoying all right let's
go again should be back up any second
and boom boom boom we got the bowtie
we got the bowtie that's all we need
okay
all right we are five minutes away from
Ren the dog being the stream master so
let's head over to him and join him in
discord and let's make some money let's
make some diamonds I've been waiting to
do this for a long time because I'm
running out of diamonds again mmm so
where's his basic I always get lost
falses bass is coming along it hadn't
changed for a really long time and now
oh now this is somewhere to fly
now I like this okay we're getting
distracted there we go let's go and hop
into the discord and I'd be something
I'm sure it's good Oh actually and hello
beautiful no no no no no no no this is
all wrong this is all wrong this is all
wrong okay this is all wrong no no no I
need to borrow would I need to borrow
would I just you know rent just hold
your horses yeah I'll fix this in a
minute I'll fix this later all right
it's really important really important
it's really important it's family off
horses are being held married to a
problem what's up okay all right let's
start again okay okay hold on maybe just
quickly don't worry I'm Wayne all right
all right all right
oh hello I'm not gonna open your door
for you so hold or rent gonna open it oh
yes oh hi oh hello good sir
good to see you good I'm trying to sell
you something wrong you don't need to
compliment me you look great oh you and
you look great by the way I'm loving
those boots
I love it oh thank you mm-hmm
handsome very handsome anyway I'm I'm
hearing your door today
- yeah ask you - get out
I've good is it the bow tie is it the
bow tie because if it's the bow tie in
the yeah the trousers were kind of
offensive so this is this is much better
much better okay anyway
so I'm here to ask you how often do you
find yourself dying in her craft
um it's hmm that's a bit of a touchy
subject for me fun honest cuz it happens
a lot
well don't worry we're in the same boat
yeah you and I were in the same dragon
skull
wait yeah yeah don't worry I'm on the
same page but boy have I got summon for
you this oh it's the did you die box it
is the kit you need when you die on
hermit craft it has Oh every my goodness
all the trinkets now you and I both know
when you die lose your stuff it's over
an hour of trying to get everything back
Oh easy easy easily so it's got Yeldon
carats you got a fully enchanted bow
trident yes you know Trident dummy I'm
sorry
one arrow - that's a great touch oh yeah
honestly it's it's all about the fine
details and the chest in there the
Electra plenty of rockets and then
you're fully inside chanted diamond gear
feather falling included aquifer tea
everything you could possibly need
mm-hmm all mending it's absolutely
beautiful
I'm not gonna lie did is this a gift is
this for me
oh no no I thinks no no I didn't come to
you I ought to give you a gift this sir
cost diodes these take a long time to
make these take a look right right now
normally well normally I charge people
three stacks of diamonds yeah but for
you there are three stacks of diamonds I
mean bro discount two and a half boom
two and a half two and a half for you
because you're a cool guy you're
handsome man
two and a half diamonds - well I thank
you baby I mean that compliment you know
I mean that kind of that was good that
was good
um I am not sure whether okay let me
just check my bank real quick um I've
only got ID okay these are all the
diamonds I have in the world right now G
all right I mean I can't look inside
your ender chest yes two stacks and 18
that is literally that is literally all
I have you know what I'm even gonna
prove it to you man it's a little light
you know it's a light on the short side
side but yeah I'm willing I'm willing Oh
I mean look
can I keep 18 I need to buy food dude
all right I'll tell you what I'll throw
in the stream de torch as well I'll take
the two stacks of diamonds you take the
box and the streamed a torch I thought
this was a negotiation is that you put
it on the table it's over like you've
accepted you know how hard I work for
those diamonds ooh that's like three
weeks of profits from the lodge well at
least you're covered really what do you
spend your diamonds on when you when you
die you have to spend a lot like that
Electra 25 diamonds and Ryder's not
usually the same yep yeah that's true
you know what like this gives me the
courage to go to the end to do some end
busting this gives me the courage to fly
around the nether it is definitely worth
the diamonds dude for shell and you know
I I know how many diamonds you've spent
on Rockets and it is absurd yeah I love
it thank you dude I will treasure in the
diamonds thank you for the day huh may I
just say for the future
okay this is the very first Sahara
customer review oh no I'm not here with
Sahara I mean I would have my uniform on
oh sorry this is this is green the
door-to-door salesman and I'm gonna take
my right well Caswell this is this is a
little bit of advice for Sahara okay
the devil is in the details my friend
this schalke box is called schalke box
not acceptable I forgot to name that one
yeah
oh I mean I don't mean to point small
detail out but um that that's that's
cost you 18 diamond and I gave you a
discount so yeah everyone's perfect say
so all in all its I think it's fair all
right in fact fine fine fine two stacks
of diamonds it is pop those in there and
hey excellent thank you thank you very
much rent and for everyone that is
watching my stream head on over to
twitch TV for slash Bren dawg I will put
a link in the chat because this stream
is officially over and I've passed the
torch over to Rend dog along with a sale
of a did you die
let's go and check him out it's hard to
read somebody from YouTube to twitch but
we're gonna try it yes I'm gonna pop a
link in there I don't even know if this
is gonna go through but there we go pop
the link in in my chat and thank you
very much for watching everyone
good luck Ren and thank you sir good
luck on your stream I will be watching
and probably annoying you oh by the way
just before you go I would like to say
that you so far have the moment of the
day in today's stream day oh yeah well
the highlight was it was just it was the
best it's moment of the day so far
amazing he's probably still jamming over
by the jukebox yeah all right thanks
everyone all righty
see you later man all right I think
that's all right everyone's still
watching please please please head on
over to read the whole point of these
stream days is that the people that are
watching get passed on over to the next
person and the next person next person
so we have like a full day so please
please please head on over there we'll
be spamming the link in the chat but
thank you very very much everyone
oh I finished thank you very very much
for watching two hours is about my limit
anyway on streaming so thank you very
much for watching everyone I hope you've
enjoyed this if you want to see more let
me know and thank you very very much to
everybody that sent in a donation I do
apologize if I missed your donation I
will be looking at all of the messages
afterwards to make sure that I read your
message personally even if I didn't say
in the chat itself so thank you thank
you thank you for all the support that
your donations are the reason that I'm
able to even do streams like this and of
course boring bye